<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>B.USOC - Belgian User Support and Operations Centre</title>
    <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/</link>
    <description>Recent content on B.USOC - Belgian User Support and Operations Centre</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</webMaster>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 1998 - 2017, B.USOC</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>History and Evolution</title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/aboutus/history/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/aboutus/history/</guid>
      <description>Evolution of the B.USOC Within the timeframe January 2013 to September 2013 and to take into account the results of the Council at ministerial level, the ESA Executive had elaborated on the USOC network, aiming to reduce operation cost and increase efficiency.
In this regard and in order to conduct operations in the European facilities on board the International Space Station (ISS), the European Space Agency had decided to implement a decentralized and hierarchical user centre approach (Figure 1).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Services</title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/aboutus/services/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/aboutus/services/</guid>
      <description>B.USOC&amp;rsquo;s prime customers are Scientific Institutions and Space Agencies with a requirement for advanced manned and non-manned space technologies not exclusively within the field of Microgravity and Space Sciences research.
Engineering Support
Our team of engineers can provide support in the following disciplines:
 Ground control Segment Design support, installation and validation Radio frequency and microwave Cryogenics and vacuum technology Real time embedded control systems Automation and Mechatronics Space mission system engineering  Knowledge Management</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Organization</title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/aboutus/organization/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/aboutus/organization/</guid>
      <description>Institutional
The B.USOC is part of the Ground Segment for the International Space Station (ISS) and is connected to the Manned Spaceflight and Microgravity (MSM) Ground Segment via the Interconnection Ground Subnetwork (IGS).
For the preparation and execution of ISS payload operations, B.USOC works together with Space Applications Services with an integrated team of operations engineers, operators and ground controllers.
The Belgian User Support and Operations Centre (B.USOC) is a structure created by the Belgian Science Policy (BELSPO) and hosted at the Royal Belgian Institute for Space Aeronomy (BIRA-IASB).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>INFRASTRUCTURE</title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/aboutus/infrastructure/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/aboutus/infrastructure/</guid>
      <description>* ESA Operations Room
      Maximize
 GC Room     Maximize
 Solar Laboratory     Maximize
 Microgravity Laboratory           </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goals and Missions</title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/aboutus/goals/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/aboutus/goals/</guid>
      <description>Our missions
 B.USOC supports scientific and technological development through high-quality space operational infrastructures and associated services, to the benefit of Belgian and European higher education and research. B.USOC promotes the development of data processing and knowledge management coming from space experiments and missions.  Our objectives
 To meet the needs of research institutions and their end users as far as space operational infrastructures and services are concerned. To promote space research to all educational and research institutions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>METERON</title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/projects/meteron/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/projects/meteron/</guid>
      <description>Start date November 01, 2011   End date January 31, 2020   Duration 3013   Discipline  Technology    Platform  International Space Station     Mars Exploration: METERON (Multi-Purpose End-To-End Robotic Operation Network) Facility Responsible Centre
The overall goal of METERON is to set up a simulation environment to allow ground controllers in a Control Centre or astronauts on ISS to be able to simulate robotic exploration scenarios tele-operating a robot located on the ground through the ISS environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Responsibilities</title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/aboutus/responsibilities/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/aboutus/responsibilities/</guid>
      <description>USOC Responsibilities
 Facility and experiment operations preparation, validation, and execution Payload increment planning and inputs to the overall mission/increment/partner plan Operations feasibility and science samples bread-boarding within the Science Reference Model (SRM), collecting science requirements for experiments and payload upgrades Consolidation planning in coordination with industry for ground model utilization (SRM/EM/EGSE) for increment preparation Provision of science/sample based parts of experiment safety data packages, experiment qualification and validation testing, experiment ground and launch site processing Update of PODF, operations scenarios with associated support centres, validation and interface testing of ground segment (Col CC, supporting USOCs, UHBs), experiment ground operations products for launch items Experiment training requirements and procedures, astronaut training support for experiment operations, including instructors, familiarization of scientists Ground-rules and constraints, issue of planning and re-planning requests, inputs to short term plans, timeline and ground data flow Real-time operations management and re-planning for payload and experiments execution, payload team and PI-team coordination, flight anomalies reporting, console logs, payload data processing, ground based experiments on SRM/EM for comparative execution Early retrieval and late access activities, configuration control of experiment ground models, and SRM configuration control  ESA/Industry Responsibilities</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SOLAR</title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/projects/solar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/projects/solar/</guid>
      <description>Solar Facility Responsible Centre
  Start date February 07, 2008   End date February 15, 2017   Duration 3296   Discipline  Space Sciences    Platform  International Space Station     For the SOLAR, three complementary space science instruments measured the solar spectral irradiance across almost the whole spectrum: 17-3000 nm. This range carried 99% of the Sun&amp;rsquo;s emitted energy. The three instruments were:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>User Home Base</title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/aboutus/uhb/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/aboutus/uhb/</guid>
      <description>For specific experiment operations, dedicated User Home Bases (UHB) have been set up when required. UHBs, which are the investigator&amp;rsquo;s location at the &amp;laquo;home&amp;raquo; institutes, are typically national institutions (e.g. universities, national centers), which need to obtain the adequate communication and data processing infrastructure allowing real-time data monitoring and control (in some cases) of the respective experiment (e.g. for remote operations).
The B.USOC coordinates and supports this setup, and is the focal point for the operations preparation activities for the UHB, more particularly for the definition of experiment operations requirements, the specifications of hardware, software and the connectivity requirements of the UHB to the ISS ground segment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/publications/pub-index/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/publications/pub-index/</guid>
      <description>We have made an inventory of the B.USOC authors publications from 2001 until now and you can access this here .
A list of B.USOC publications is also available on orfeo from KBR
2001 Exobiology: Martian Environmental Conditions
2003 STERILISATION PROPERTIES OF THE MARS SURFACE AND ATMOSPHERIC ENVIRONMENT
2004 Telescience and Space Missions Operations at the Belgian User Support and Operation Centre
Le vol habité vers Mars : une étude de l&amp;rsquo;ESA</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/projects/home/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/projects/home/</guid>
      <description>.plusieurs_colonnes{ -moz-column-count: 4; -moz-column-gap: 20px; -webkit-column-count:4; -webkit-column-gap: 20px; column-count:4; column-gap: 20px; list-style: none; } .fourcolumns { -moz-column-count:4; -moz-column-gap: 5px; -webkit-column-count: 4 ; -webkit-column-gap: 20px; column-count:4; column-gap: 20px; list-style: none; ; } @media (max-width: 767px) { .plusieurs_colonnes{ -moz-column-count: 1; -moz-column-gap: 5px; -webkit-column-count: 1 ; -webkit-column-gap: 20px; column-count:1; column-gap: 20px; list-style: none;
} .fourcolumns { -moz-column-count: 1; -moz-column-gap: 5px; -webkit-column-count: 1 ; -webkit-column-gap: 20px; column-count:1; column-gap: 20px; list-style: none; ; } }    EPT</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happy New Year 2019</title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/55/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/55/</guid>
      <description>   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FSL - SMD (Soft matter dynamics)</title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/projects/fsl-project/smd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/projects/fsl-project/smd/</guid>
      <description>The experiment container SMD is a class 2 payload which can be inserted in the FSL Laboratory. SMD allows to study foams, emulsions and granular matters in microgravity. The container provides optical microscope, single and multi specke diffusing wave spectroscopy, supporting also time resolved correlations, to investigate primarily dynamics on the surface of and inside opaque but translucent materials.
The experiment container can be extended with on-orbit replaceable science cartridges.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CUBIST</title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/projects/cubist/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/projects/cubist/</guid>
      <description>Start date January 01, 2010   End date December 31, 2013   Duration 1460   Discipline  Knowledge management    Platform  International Space Station     CUBIST was a research-project, funded by the European Commission, and conducted by several partners coming from different European Countries (Germany, France, the UK, Belgium and Bulgaria). CUBIST envisioned combining the two worlds of Business Intelligence and Semantic Technologies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ODISSEA</title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/projects/odissea/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/projects/odissea/</guid>
      <description>Start date November 01, 2002   End date November 17, 2002   Duration 16   Discipline  Microgravity    Platform  International Space Station     European Space Agency (ESA) astronaut Frank De Winne, of Belgian nationality, flew to the International Space Station (ISS) in late October 2002 on board a Russian Soyuz taxi flight. He became the first Belgian to visit the ISS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CUBESAT network (QB50)</title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/projects/qb50/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/projects/qb50/</guid>
      <description>Start date November 01, 2011   End date January 31, 2016   Duration 1552   Discipline  Earth Observation    Platform  Cubesat     QB50 had the scientific objective to study in situ the temporal and spatial variations of a number of key constituents and parameters in the lower thermosphere (90-320 km) with a network of about 40 double CubeSats, separated by a few hundred kilometers and carrying identical sensors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EANA</title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/projects/eana/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/projects/eana/</guid>
      <description>Start date October 25, 2000   End date October 25, 2020   Duration 7305   Discipline  Knowledge management    Platform  International Space Station     International Networking: EANA: European Astrobiology Network Association. In the frame of the ISS programme, ESA requested to ensure the promotion of USOC activities towards scientists using the ISS. This objective was reached for the B.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PERICLES</title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/projects/pericles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/projects/pericles/</guid>
      <description>Start date January 01, 2013   End date March 31, 2017   Duration 1550   Discipline  Knowledge management    Platform  International Space Station     PERICLES did not want to invent another preservation system. It wanted to understand how to realize a world where preservation policies - human-defined, human-understandable policies- could shape and change a model of preservation that should, consequently, be implemented in a dynamic architecture with no reliance on any particular computational component.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TOSCA</title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/projects/tosca/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/projects/tosca/</guid>
      <description>Start date October 25, 2012   End date October 25, 2015   Duration 1095   Discipline  Knowledge management    Platform  International Space Station     COST actions: COST –ES 10005 (TOSCA) “Towards a more complete assessment of the impact of solar variability on the Earth’s climate”.
This action increased the visibility of SOLAR as requested by ESA and allowed the participation of B.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ulisse</title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/projects/ulisse/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/projects/ulisse/</guid>
      <description>Start date January 01, 2010   End date December 31, 2012   Duration 1095   Discipline  Knowledge management    Platform  International Space Station     SUVIM was a Belgian Institute for Space Aeronomy (IASB-BIRA) network of stations measuring UV solar radiation with several instruments at each station. The network produced several UV radiation group at IASB-BIRA and provided UV indexes and solar irradiances at the stations in quasi-real time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ALTIUS</title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/projects/altius/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/projects/altius/</guid>
      <description>Start date December 31, 2016   End date December 31, 2020   Duration 1462   Discipline  Earth Observation    Platform  micro-satellite of the PROBA class     The ALTIUS instrument observing the earth upper atmospheric composition has been now included in the ESA earthwatch programme, B.USOC will operate an ALTIUS science centre in close cooperation with the BIRA-IASB team which initiated the project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASIM</title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/projects/asim/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/projects/asim/</guid>
      <description>Start date April 13, 2018   End date January 31, 2020   Duration 658   Discipline  Space Sciences    Platform  International Space Station     ASIM Facility Responsible Centre
ASIM is an ESA science instrument assembly to be flown on the Columbus External Platform Facility (CEPF) of the ISS (International Space Station). The ASIM concept has been proposed by DNSC (Danish National Space Centre, formerly DSRI (Danish Space Research Institute)), with the objective to observe TLEs (Transient Luminous Events) that occur in the Earth&amp;rsquo;s upper atmosphere accompanied by thunderstorms in the lower atmosphere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NOMAD</title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/projects/nomad/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/projects/nomad/</guid>
      <description>Start date March 14, 2016   End date December 31, 2022   Duration 2484   Discipline  Exploration    Platform  ExoMars Trace Gas Orbiter (TGO)     NOMAD is a payload of the Trace Gas Orbiter (TGO) which is part of the ESA EXOMARS project. TGO has reached his science orbit around Mars during 2018 and as NOMAD has a Belgian Principal Investigator from BIRA-IASB, B.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Space Pole and B.USOC 2018 Open doors</title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/53/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/53/</guid>
      <description>Saturday 29 and Sunday 30 September 2018 , B.USOC and Space Pole in Uccle (Brussels) opened doors to the public. People saw a little operations centre with timeline , tools example and videos of ASIM and FSL project.
  B.USOC team was available to explain and reply to questions about B.USOC and projects : FSL and ASIM.
  The models of SOLAR, ASIM and GEOFLOW of FSL were exposed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FSL</title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/projects/fsl/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/projects/fsl/</guid>
      <description>Start date October 01, 2013   End date January 31, 2020   Duration 2313   Discipline  Microgravity    Platform  International Space Station     The Fluid Science Laboratory is a multi-user facility to study the dynamics of fluids in the absence of gravity.
The B.USOC is the control and command centre for FSL. It sends telecommands, receives telemetries and transfers the data to the scientists.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASTROMAP</title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/projects/astromap/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/projects/astromap/</guid>
      <description>Start date November 01, 2011   End date March 01, 2015   Duration 1216   Discipline  Space Sciences    Platform  International Space Station     A FP-7 project to support the European astrobiology network including a mandate to draft a roadmap for astrobiology which was used for the definition of the HORIZON 2020 programme.
The programme began in early 2013 and organized 4 thematic road mapping workshops.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HAM VIDEO</title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/projects/hamvideo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/projects/hamvideo/</guid>
      <description>Informations    Start date January 01, 2013   End date December 31, 2014   Duration 729   Discipline  Technology    Platform  International Space Station       The objective of the Ham Video On-Orbit Functional Commissioning was to install in Columbus and test the functionalities of the Ham Video hardware and the related on-orbit equipment. After successful performance of the above objective, the Ham Video Flight Segment could be declared functional and ready to be used by Amateur Radio on the International Space Station (ARISS).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PICARD</title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/projects/picard/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/projects/picard/</guid>
      <description>Start date June 15, 2010   End date March 01, 2015   Duration 1720   Discipline  Space Sciences    Platform  Myriade     Picard was a microsatellite sending back data needed to improve models used for forecasting solar activity. It was designed to take simultaneous measurements of parameters such as the speed at which the Sun rotates, the radiation it emits, the presence of sunspots and its shape and diameter, to help scientists understand the relationship between them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Communications of B.USOC and Space Situational Awareness Center at the 15th SpaceOps 2018 in Marseille</title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/52/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/52/</guid>
      <description>SpaceOps 2018 is a technical forum of the Space Mission Operations and Ground Systems community that addresses state-of-the-art operations principles, methods, and tools. Held biennially, the conference attracts technologists, scientists, managers from agencies, academic and research institutions, operators and industry to share their mission’s experience, challenges, and innovation solutions. At SpaceOps 2018, B.USOC and Space Applications make a presentation about SOLAR project : download here .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New instrument ASIM in the ISS to observe thunderstorms</title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/51/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/51/</guid>
      <description>ASIM (Atmosphere-Space Interactions Monitor) was arrived on April 13, 2018 on the International Space Station (ISS).
This instrument can observe TLE (transient luminous events) and TGF ( Terrestrial gamma-ray flashes ) for a better understanding of the influence of violent storms on the atmosphere and the climate on Earth.
B.USOC is the ESA responsible center for the ASIM infrastructure :
 receiving the telemetries, monitoring the instrument delivering the data to ASIM Science Data Centre in Denmark.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Group of Ambassadors to UN visiting B.USOC in parallel to the 10th Conference on European Space Policy</title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/50/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/50/</guid>
      <description>A delegation of UN Ambassadors to the Business Bridge Europe Space Conference organised by the European Union in Brussels has visited B.USOC yesterday as an example of successful European space cooperation in the frame of ESA and the E.U.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happy New Year 2018</title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/54/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/54/</guid>
      <description>   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Belgium from space  shines more than its neighbours</title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/49/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/49/</guid>
      <description>Astronaut Thomas Pesquet took impressive photos of Europe from space with Belgium up and Warsaw below. We also see aurora borealis in the background. It denounces the waste of light pollution in Belgium: with 186 bulbs per square mile even on small country roads, the country is the leader unrivalled in Western Europe. Beside, France seems to have been cast in the darkness. Thomas Pesquet returns to Earth on June 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> B.USOC presentation at the May 20 VVS meeting in Ghent</title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/48/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/48/</guid>
      <description>The astronautics working group of the VVS (Vereniging Voor Sterrenkunde) meets in Ghent on May 20 with several lectures on manned space exploration. ( http://www.vvs.be/werkgroepen/werkgroep-ruimtevaart/ruimtevaartnamiddag-zaterdag-20-mei-2017 ).
B.USOC will be presented by Geraldine Mariën (Space Applications Services) under the title &amp;laquo;B.USOC, een mini-Houston in België&amp;raquo;.
This lecture will describe the tasks and the work days of the B.USOC operators and personnel together with the international structure of the ISS and its Belgian contributions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PERICLES</title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/47/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/47/</guid>
      <description>Pericles:Promoting and Enhancing Reuse of Information throughout the Content Lifecycle taking account of Evolving Semantics
B.USOC participated in the FP-7 PERICLES project from February 2013 to its end in April 2017. PERICLES was coordinated by King’s College London, UK and its partners are University of Borås (Sweden), CERTH- ITI (Greece), DotSoft (Greece), Georg-August-Universität Göttingen (Germany), University of Liverpool (UK), Space Application Services (Belgium), XEROX France and University of Edinburgh (UK).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BRAMS</title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/projects/brams/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/projects/brams/</guid>
      <description>Start date January 1, 2010   End date August 12,2016   Duration 2416   Discipline  Space sciences    Platform  International Space Station     BRAMS (Belgian RAdio Meteor Stations) was a radio set receiving stations using forward scattering techniques to study the meteoroids population. The project was coordinated by the Royal Belgian Institute for Space Aeronomy (BISA), within the framework of the Solar-Terrestrial Centre of Excellence (STCE).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/contacts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/contacts/</guid>
      <description>The Belgian User Support and Operation Centre (B.USOC) is located in Uccle, in the premises of the Belgian Institute for Space Aeronomy (BIRA-IASB).
3 avenue circulaire
1180-Uccle
Brussels
phone: +32.2.373.04.87
fax: +32.2.373.04.52
 Our teams  td { width:50%; }   B.USOC    Alexis Muller Web designer   Alice Michel Project manager/Operations manager   André Somerhausen Ground Controller   Anuschka Helderweirt Scientific operator   Christian Noel Back office support   Claudio Queirolo Scientific operator   Dirk Pauwels Ground Controller   Etienne Haumont Product and quality assurance   Jessica Bevernaegie Administrative support   Karim Litefti Ground segment manager   Loick Marcourt Ground Controller   Michel Kruglanski Manager   Nicolas Brun S/W Developer   Sven De Ridder Scientific operator     Space Applications Services    Alejandro Diaz Ground Controller   Alexander Karl Operations Engineer   Carla Jacobs Operations Engineer   Denis Vanhoof Operations Engineer   Gabriele conti Operations Engineer   Geraldine Marien Operations Engineer   Julien Dufey Operations Engineer   Kevin Voet Operations Engineer   Koen Struyven Operations Engineer   Lode Pieters Operations Engineer   Nicolae Mihalache Developer   Olivier Lamborelle Backup Project Manager   Saliha Klai Operations Manager   Tom Van Braeckel Ground Controller    Partners</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EPT</title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/projects/ept/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/projects/ept/</guid>
      <description>Start date May 02, 2013   End date May 02, 2018   Duration 1826   Discipline  Earth Observation    Platform  Planetary Operations : Proba     During PROBA-V mission, the Energetic Particle Telescope (EPT) will measure the high-energy particle fluxes with very good energy, angular and mass resolutions. It measures the energy deposited by charged particles into twelve sensitive elements and processes the information to identify the particles (0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KUPS</title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/projects/kups/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/projects/kups/</guid>
      <description>Start date October 31, 2010   End date November 6, 2012   Duration 311   Discipline  Space sciences    Platform  International Space Station     The Portable Power Supply was an autonomous converter unit to distribute 28VDC to one or more payloads (up to three) taking the upstream power 120VDC provided by ISS Columbus Module SUP.
KuPS was composed of a metal box containing all the required electronic parts and provided of interface connectors, on/off manual switches and autonomous cooling system (forced air convection).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LESS &amp; EPO</title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/projects/lessepo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/projects/lessepo/</guid>
      <description>Start date August 29, 2009   End date December 1,2009   Duration 95   Discipline  Space sciences    Platform  International Space Station     EPO3 Water properties In the context of collaboration between ESA and UNICEF an overview lecture was given with demonstration of various water properties. The recording of the demonstration was used to produce ESA educational multimedia material for upper primary school teachers and their students aged 10-12.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neurocog / Cardiocog</title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/projects/neurocog-cardiocog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/projects/neurocog-cardiocog/</guid>
      <description>Start date May 4, 2004   End date October 19,2004   Duration 168   Discipline  Space sciences    Platform  International Space Station     During the Increment 9 of the ISS utilization, two experiments with Belgian participation were hold in the Russian module: Neurocog (ULB, CNRS and CNES) and Cardiocog (KULeuven University and CNES). For both expeditions 9 crew members were taking part to these experiments, among them Russian cosmonaut Gennady I.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PLEIADES LTDP service</title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/projects/pleiades/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/projects/pleiades/</guid>
      <description>Start date March 01, 2013   End date December 31, 2020   Duration 2861   Discipline  Earth Observation    Platform  Pleiades     In 2006, the Belgium government and the French government signed an additional clause to their initial agreement related to the participation of Belgium in the Spot Programme allowing Belgium to participate in the Pleiades programme as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project</title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/projects/cmsp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/projects/cmsp/</guid>
      <description>PICARD   Start date June 15, 2010   End date March 01, 2015   Duration 1719   Discipline  Space Sciences     Platform  Myriade      Picard is a microsatellite sending back data needed to improve models used for forecasting solar activity. It was designed to take simultaneous measurements of parameters such as the speed at which the Sun rotates, the radiation it emits, the presence of sunspots and its shape and diameter, to help scientists understand the relationship between them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PromISS-4</title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/projects/promiss4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/projects/promiss4/</guid>
      <description>Start date December 21, 2005   End date April 1, 2006   Duration 101   Discipline  Microgravity    Platform  International Space Station     PromISS-4 was a Belgian experiment in the International Space Station (ISS) launched with the Progress 20P on 21rst December 2005. Its main scientific objectives were to study proteins, to obtain in microgravity better crystals, to understand protein crystal growth processes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SOLCON</title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/projects/solcon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/projects/solcon/</guid>
      <description>Start date January 16, 2003   End date February 1,2003   Duration 16   Discipline  Space sciences    Platform  Atlas spacelab     From January 16th 2003 to February 1st 2003, B-USOC hosted the Belgian Remote SOLCON Payload Operation and Control Centre (POCC), which was the only European PI Centre involved and being directly connected to NASA HitchHiker operation networks (via the ESA IGS network, managed by ESOC IGS control team).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SOLCON</title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/projects/sts107/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/projects/sts107/</guid>
      <description>Start date January 16, 2003   End date February 1,2003   Duration 16   Discipline  Space sciences    Platform  Atlas spacelab     From January 16th 2003 to February 1st 2003, B-USOC hosted the Belgian Remote SOLCON Payload Operation and Control Centre (POCC), which was the only European PI Centre involved and being directly connected to NASA HitchHiker operation networks (via the ESA IGS network, managed by ESOC IGS control team).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taste in space</title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/projects/tasteinspace/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/projects/tasteinspace/</guid>
      <description>Start date March 18, 2010   End date March 16,2011   Duration 364   Discipline  Space sciences    Platform  International Space Station     The activity was aiming to demonstrate to primary school students the differences in the way in which the sense of taste is affected under weightless conditions and on Earth by comparing the results of a blind tasting of 6 different food items on the ground and in space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is the B.USOC</title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/aboutus/about-index/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/aboutus/about-index/</guid>
      <description>B.USOC is a services centre of the Belgian Science Policy (BELSPO)/R&amp;amp;S division. Our mission is to provide operational services for Belgian scientific institutions and space agencies.
Our dedicated engineering and operations teams carry out experiments on board the International Space Station (ISS) and Satellite ranging from the integration of payloads to their in-orbit operation, astronaut training, processing and dissemination of the scientific data obtained.
B.USOC in short :
 15 years of experience in preparation and operations of ESA experiments &amp;amp; missions Highly experienced engineers, technicians and scientists Ground Control Segment Design support, Installation and Validation Knowledge and Experience in satellite commissioning and operations First decentralized Science Operations Centre for CNES PICARD micro-satellite Assigned by ESA as Facility Responsible Center for ESA/ISS/SOLAR-FSL-METERON-ASIM Knowledge management service focusing on improved performance  About us :</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Farewell SOLAR!</title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/46/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/46/</guid>
      <description>An event is scheduled in Brussels to share memories with all actors involved in the adventure.
Take part to the farewell event : https://events.oma.be/indico/event/22/
You will can also follow the event on https://livestream.com/ESA/solar
Solar Posters created for the event here
@media (max-width: 767px) {iframe {width:360px;} }</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First RUBI tests at B.USOC</title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/45/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/45/</guid>
      <description>During the week 2 of January 2017 (Monday 9 to Friday 13), the EM of the RUBI experiment container was tested at B.USOC for the first time, inside the FSL-EM, by TAS-I and Airbus DS.
The electrical &amp;amp; interfaces Tests were all successful.
Currently, the RUBI experiment execution target date in the International Space Station is fixed in December 2018. The RUBI experiment container being launched to the Space Station with Space X-17 rocket.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best Wishes for 2017 !</title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/44/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/44/</guid>
      <description>To illustrate 2016 and to celebrate the new year , we show you a picture from the Mars Yard in United Kingdom, when USA astronaut Tim Peake controlled the rover , Bridget (2016 April 29), from the ISS during the METERON SUPVIS-M experiment . Credit : ESA.
The whish card 2017 is here: https://flic.kr/p/PCmjc5
   The background wallpaper for your screen is here: https://flic.kr/p/PFzG1R
   The original picture is from the flickr account @esa_events : https://www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geoflow operational on Fluid Science Laboratory</title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/43/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/43/</guid>
      <description>Science is running again on FSL! The Fluid Science Laboratory, onboard Columbus, was failing to downlink High Rate data for quite some time.
But yesterday, a workaround to get scientific videos on the ground was finally put in place and tested successfully with the Geoflow experiment, thanks to the perseverance and dedication of B.USOC engineers, professionalism of Airbus (Bremen) and of the Spanish USOC (E.USOC), and the great support and flexibility of the Columbus Control Centre.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Session in Ostend about how we use space weather tools at BUSOC!</title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/42/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/42/</guid>
      <description>How Space Weather affects International Space Station is a session at B.USOC and has been presented by Carla Jacobs (B.USOC,Space Applications Services) during 13th European Space Weather Week (ESWW) , at Ostend on November 14 2016.
  This tutorial was intended for other users of space weather forecasts.   More info: http://www.stce.be/esww13/press.php
Link to the presentation of Carla Jacobs</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMU2 Crew Inspection on Aug 9 2016</title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/41/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/41/</guid>
      <description>   Pedro Duque (crew representative) checked the VMU2 for its operationality (crew access to the unit, mating-demating of harnesses convenience) with respect to the crew activity in the ISS.
VMU2 will replace the current VMU (Video Management Unit) in the FSL in 2017.
Honoured to have @astro_duque with us @busoc_official yesterday for an #FSL #ISS crew inspection pic.twitter.com/Q57kQbGHau
&amp;mdash; aeronomie.be (@BIRA_IASB) August 10, 2016  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Return of astronaut Tim Peake</title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/40/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/40/</guid>
      <description>The ESA British astronaut Tim Peake landed on June 18 after an extremely successful science mission oriented in large part towards the future manned exploration programme.
He conducted ESA experiments and the METERON Supvis-M test of driving a Martian lander mockup from the ISS in a realistic set-up in the dark.
Much more details can be seen on the mission web site: https://principia.org.uk/the-mission/ and http://blogs.esa.int/tim-peake/</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The PERICLES Project shows a video of SOLAR</title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/39/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/39/</guid>
      <description>The PERICLES project posted the following video at the Open Science session of the recent Living Planet Symposium organised by ESA in Prague.
This video is on the study of preservation of SOLAR data by B.USOC:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CANADARM images SOLAR</title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/38/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/38/</guid>
      <description>New SOLAR Pictures
During a COLUMBUS survey, the CANADARM robot imaged SOLAR in flight on May 4, SOLAR is flying on the ISS since February 2008 with B.USOC support and monitors the spectral irradiance of the sun.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>METERON Operations on April 29</title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/37/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/37/</guid>
      <description>   The path of the Bridget rover that Tim Peake drove from the ISS on April 29 2016.
The orange crosses correspond to annotations made by Tim Peake when finding a target (red dot or cross).
Maximize the picture : https://flic.kr/p/GRdGqr
   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>METERON SUPVIS-M (29/04/2016)</title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/36/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/36/</guid>
      <description>On April 29, British astronaut Tim Peake drove a rover named Bridget in the Mars Yard at Stevenage, UK from the International Space Station as part of the METERON project that is preparing for future human-robotic missions to the Moon, Mars and beyond. He had the challenging task of driving a rover across a sandpit that resembles the Martian surface. Bridget is a development model of the ESA EXOMARS mission.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>B.USOC is happily and proudly starting the 100th Sun Visibility Window of SOLAR</title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/35/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/35/</guid>
      <description>This Observatory onboard the ISS is tracking the Sun now for more than 8 years!
The instrument was designed to work for only 18 months, but it is still running â€“ its operation is exceeding all expectations. Launched at the 2008 minimum of solar cycle 23, it observed the also the maximum of solar cycle 24 in 2015 and now is still active in the decrease phase. Solar energy input to the earth atmosphere and its variations are a major factor in the climate models and are accurately monitored only since the beginning of the space age.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SOLAR in the ISS observes the March 8 total eclipse of the sun</title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/34/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/34/</guid>
      <description>The SOLAR package was active during the March 8 eclipse over Indonesia and measured the progressive dimming of the sun by the moon in three wavelengths, this observation is of course non nominal but analysis by the SOLSPEC science team has already started in order to check the theoretical representation of the spatial distribution of the solar radiation on the solar disk, the observation could also be used in order to perform a verification of the value of the solar diameter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installation and Removal of CIMEX</title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/33/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/33/</guid>
      <description>   CIMEX (Convective Interfacial Mass EXperiment) is a MAP research program (Microgravity Application Promotion) funded by ESA and BELSPO and studies studies phase change phenomena and mass transfer through liquid-gas and liquid-liquid interfaces.
The removal of CIMEX scheduled from monday 18/01 to friday 22/01/2016.
More info:
https://www.ulb.ac.be/rech/inventaire/chercheurs/7/CH5947.html
http://reports.nlr.nl/xmlui/bitstream/handle/10921/898/TP-2000-702.pdf?sequence=1
http://www.esa.int/spaceinimages/Images/2009/10/CIMEX_setup_click_to_access_larger_download
Pictures of installation of CIMEX.
 Pictures of the removal of CIMEX EA from FSL EM.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2/11/2000 : 15 years of continuous ISS manned operations</title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/32/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/32/</guid>
      <description>It was November 2/11/2000 that the first crew arrived at the ISS shown here in its first expedition configuration.
The three first ISS astronauts were : William Shepherd (commander, NASA), Sergei K.Krikalev (RSA) et Yuri Gidzenko (RSA). They prepared the station for further occupations and began the science programme of the ISS, since them a rotating cast of more than 220 of the world&amp;rsquo;s elite astronauts have lived and worked at the ISS, which includes 16 participating nations and is led by the United States and Russia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>THOR - METERON - What a day!</title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/31/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/31/</guid>
      <description>Tuesday 8 September 2015 will stay in the memories of many B.USOC operators for a long time! On that day, Flight Day 7 of the Short Duration Mission of the Danish astronaut Andreas Mogensen onboard the ISS, the operator team was engaged in two experiments successfully achieved.
That day, at the Belgian Control Centre, the SUPVIS-E experiment was accomplished with great success. The activity consisted of Andreas controlling the Eurobot rover located at ESTEC and executing a scenario including multiple robotic assets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Danish Astronaut Andreas Mogensen ready to conduct METERON and science operations from the ISS</title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/30/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/30/</guid>
      <description>Danish Astronaut Andreas Mogensen ready to conduct METERON and science operations from the ISS. The launch is scheduled on September 2.
On September 2, Danish ESA astronaut Andreas Mogensen will leave on a SOYUZ rocket to the ISS with fellow astronauts Sergei Volkov and Aidyn Aimbetov. During his stay on board the ISS, he will control the EUROBOT robot on ground at ESTEC in the METERON programme, with a new communications protocol adapted for space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First command to the FSL in the ISS</title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/28/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/28/</guid>
      <description>April 21, 2015: first command sent to B.USOC to the ISS Fluid Science Laboratory (FSL).
In the morning of April 21, the B.USOC team successfully activated the FSL module in COLUMBUS and both sent test commands and received ancillary data leading to the start of a new activity in B.USOC. This successful end to end test prepares future science operations and is currently analysed in details.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>March 20 eclipse of the sun</title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/27/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/27/</guid>
      <description>SOLAR on the ISS will observe the March 20 eclipse on the sun.
On March 20, there will be a coincidence between the International Space Station orbit and the path of the solar eclipse in Northern Africa. The SOLAR package on the ESA COLUMBUS module of the ISS will observe it. SOLAR operates for 7 years in earth orbit and measures the energy emitted by the sun for the far ultraviolet to the infrared in order to monitor the solar influence on atmospheric chemistry and climate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Download UV DATA&amp;graphics from the Ulisse website</title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/26/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/26/</guid>
      <description>The project ULISSE intends to distribute all the original UV data obtained since 1993 in the frame of the ULISSE metadata.
The project ULISSE intends to distribute all the original UV data obtained since 1993 in the frame of the ULISSE metadata.
SUVIM is a Belgian Institute for Space Aeronomy (IASB-BIRA) network of stations measuring UV solar radiation with several instruments at each station, the network produces several UV radiation group at IASB-BIRA and providing UV indexes and solar irradiances at the stations in quasi-real time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>B.USOC 15 years Open Doors 2014 </title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/23/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/23/</guid>
      <description>The Belgian Institute for Space Aeronomy turns 50 years : Open Doors are possible on 11 and 12 October 2014.
The BUSOC hosted by BIRA participates also at the event.
The BUSOC will propose to read the comicbook of the TOSCA project and activities about projects of BUSOC (original in english and translation in french)
The B.USOC also turns 15 years. At this occasion, a a game book FR - NL ( corrections in French and Dutch ) has been created covering the most important projects in which B.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get your first boarding pass to Mars</title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/25/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/25/</guid>
      <description>NASA has developed a new manned spacecraft: ORION which will be the first since APOLLO to travel beyond the earth orbit with the moon, Mars or asteroids as destinations. These exploration targets are the future of manned exploration. The first unmanned test flight will take place in December this year from NASA Kennedy Space Center to recovery at sea in the Pacific Ocean.
Even without a payload we can participate by having NASA write our name on a memory chip which will be carried by ORION</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Team Building Activity at Euro Space Center</title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/24/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/24/</guid>
      <description>Friday September 19, the B.USOC team will participate to a team building activity at Euro space center in Redu (Luxembourg-Belgium) during 2h30.
&amp;laquo;EURO SPACE CENTER is a discovery and recreation centre on the theme of space exploration and its impact on our daily lives.&amp;raquo;
The Euro Space Center propose to B.USOC a VIP Tour with a guided tour of &amp;laquo;A Space Odyssey&amp;raquo; and at the end the possibility to test two training machines used by astronauts: the moonwalk simulates walking on the Moon and the multi-axis chair recreates the feeling of disorientation felt in space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NASA Challenge : How will space , science and technology benefit humanity? </title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/22/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/22/</guid>
      <description>The NASA and his &amp;laquo;Humans in Space Art Program&amp;raquo; organize a call to creativity for college students and early career professional and invite to think about the benefits of the space for the humanity.
Any style are allowed (animation, sketches, music , drama, poetry, dance,etc). The deadline November 15.
More information on http://www.lpi.usra.edu/humansinspaceart/challenge/
Download the poster in french and english here :
http://www.lpi.usra.edu/humansinspaceart/challenge/poster/
Be inspired and Good Luck !</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>METERON: OPSCOM-2-video</title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/21/</guid>
      <description>=
After the successful OPSCOM-2 test of August 7, ESA released a video showing the complex operations of the EUROBOT in ESTEC commanded by astronaut Alexander Gerst from the ISS using the Disruptive/Delay Tolerant Network (DTN) communication protocol.
METERON is a programme common to the ISS space agencies: NASA, ESA, Roscosmos and DLR developing the technology necessary for this objective by commanding a robot on earth by an astronaut on the ISS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>METERON: OPSCOM-2</title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/20/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/20/</guid>
      <description>Future human space exploration will most likely involve sending robots to explore the planetary surface, in preparation and support of the on-site exploration by humans.
The Meteron project is exactly preparing for that future. Use of robots will continue even when humans have safely landed for both astronaut support and planetary protection of â€œspecial regionsâ€ defined by the international treaties as hospitable for elementary life. Controlling the robots, even for short distances, would require a form of reliable internet to send commands and to receive information back.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The SOLAR payload on the ISS.Fourth bridging operation</title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/19/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/19/</guid>
      <description>The SOLAR payload, located on one of the four external platforms of the Columbus module on the International Space Station, is active since February 2008 and measures the solar spectral irradiance with two instruments : SOLSPEC which covers the spectral range of the Ultra-Violet (UV) to the near infrared and SOL-ACES, a set of spectrometers measuring the Extreme UV radiation (EUV).
Due to the characteristics of the ISS orbit and the mechanical limitations for the platform, at most 20 minutes of measurements are possible per ISS revolution, and this for only 10 to 12 consecutive days per month.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>B.USOC role in the ASIM operations on the ISS</title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/17/</guid>
      <description>ASIM is an ISS science payload aimed principally at the observation of Transitory Light Events (TLE) occurring over intense thunderstorms lightning. ASIM observes also TGF’s (terrestrial gamma rays flashes which are also related to strong lightning. It has been proposed by the Danish scientist Torsten Neubert and is due for launch in 2016. B.USOC is Facility Responsible Centre (FRC) for this payload.
The ASIM mission constitutes of a package of two nadir instruments : one for the visible and another for the X ray and radio frequencies, the normal operating mode is a trigger mode where both instruments are continuously measuring but do not record data below thresholds to be determined by the science team.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Successful HDEV installation on Columbus platform</title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/16/</guid>
      <description>Wednesday 30 April, the NASA Payload, HDEV was successfully installed on the Nadir external platform of Columbus. During the installation SOLAR (on the zenith position) had to be completely switched off (survival heaters included) for about 30 minutes.
HDEV payload is hosting video cameras looking at the Earth, live stream from the cameras can be seen here: http://www.ustream.tv/channel/iss-hdev-payload</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ham Video commissioning completed successfully! </title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/15/</guid>
      <description>Four ARISS ground stations (Poitiers, Bornemouth, Casale Monferrato and Livorno) took part in this final pass, and all together recorded the transmitted video and audio signal of about 6 minutes:
  B.USOC was very proud to coordinate these Ham Video commissioning activities for ARISS, on behalf of ESA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Ham Video tests on-board ISS, so far so good!</title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/14/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/14/</guid>
      <description>Thanks to the American astronaut Michael Hopkins, and the operators teams on the ground, B.USOC in close collaboration with ARISS grounds stations spread over Italy. The last pass of Ham Video commissioning is foreseen in April-May timeframe, with the Japanese taïkonaute Koichi Wakata.
See more information here: http://www.ariss-eu.org/
http://amsat-uk.org/2014/03/08/iss-hamtv-success/</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The new cooling pump allows again full power for ISS payloads</title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/10/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/10/</guid>
      <description>On December 26, the new cooling pump for the second electrical circuit was put in service after two spacewalks&amp;hellip;
On December 26, the new cooling pump for the second electrical circuit was put in service after two spacewalks and the full power could be restored on the station scientific payloads including the SOLAR package. SOLAR could be tested and will restart observations at the next solar visibility window this January.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>temporary interruption of SOLAR due to partial cooling failure</title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/9/</guid>
      <description>On Wednesday December 11, the pump module on one of the space station’s two external cooling loops automatically shut down when it reached pre-set temperature limits. These loops circulate ammonia outside the station to keep both internal and external equipment cool.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spacelab</title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/5/</guid>
      <description>Spacelab and 30 years of ESA astronauts
SPACELAB-1 was the first manned space mission involving several Belgian experiments in earth sciences, solar physics, microgravity and life sciences. In particular, two external payloads: SOLSPEC and SOLCON were quasi identical to instruments flown presently on the SOLAR payload on the ISS and which continue the series of solar irradiance observations initiated by this first mission.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>REVEX picard 2013</title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/8/</guid>
      <description>It is a review of the PICARD operations of 2013.
This review took place on November 27.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New website Pleiades</title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/12/</guid>
      <description>B.USOC distributes Pléiades images already bought and exploited by Belgian customers through the BELSPO STEREO programme.
B.USOC distributes Pléiades images already bought and exploited by Belgian customers through the BELSPO STEREO programme. The CNES-European Union Pléiades 1A and Pléiades 1B satellites operate as a constellation in the same orbit, phased 180° apart. The identical twin satellites deliver very-high-resolution optical data products in record time and offer a daily revisit capability to any point on the globe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Space Pole Opendoors</title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/11/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/11/</guid>
      <description>Saturday 25 and Sunday 26 may , Busoc and Space Pole in Uccle (Brussels) opened doors to the public.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SOLAR on the ISS resumes normal operations after replacement of a leaking cooling pump on the ISS.</title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/7/</guid>
      <description>The ISS astronauts stopped an ammonia leak in the ISS external cooling loop by replacing a suspected pump unit by the spare one and checking all connections on Saturday May 11.
http://www.nasa.gov/mission_pages/station/expeditions/expedition35/e35_051113_eva.html
This leak had appeared on May 9 and posed a threat to the ISS power conditioning as the main function of this cooling loop is to control the temperature of the electrical motors moving the solar panels. The coolant lines will have to be monitored for several weeks before it is certain that the leak has been fully fixed by the replacement and maintenance EVA of May 11.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KuPS successfully installed on the ISS November</title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/6/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday, Novembert 6th, the Portable Pwr Supply (KuPS) was installed successfully on the ISS. Portable Pwr Supply, as the name says, provides power to experiments. The first experiment attached to Portable Pwr Supply is TRITEL, which will monitor the radiation environment in the European Columbus module. TRITEL was also installed yesterday, and will run for 6 months.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Belgian Operations Center gets the ISS rotated</title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/2/</guid>
      <description>SOLAR was installed on Columbus the same day the module itself was attached to the other modules of the space station. Being in space since February 2008, SOLAR will soon be celebrating its 5th birthday. &amp;laquo;This is quite an achievement&amp;raquo;, says Nadia This, operations engineer at B.USOC, &amp;laquo;since SOLAR was designed to operate for 18 months only.&amp;raquo;
The instruments on SOLAR observe the Sun, and due to the movement of the ISS, the instruments must be kept pointed at the Sun actively with a rotating platform, SOLAR.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SOLAR - Second mission extension achieved</title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/3/</guid>
      <description>Last week, the Safety Review approved the second extension of the SOLAR mission, until February 2017. SOLAR installed on the external platform of Columbus in February 2008 for a nominal mission of one year and half, and was soon extended over February 2013.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SOLAR SOLSPEC collaborating with Venus Express</title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/1/</guid>
      <description>On May 17th, a unique collaboration between instruments on the ISS and Venus Express was set up. Between 19h00 and 22h30, SOLSPEC, in Earth-orbit on the ISS, and SPICAV, in Venus-orbit on Venus Express, were simultaneously observing the sun. The goal of this synchronisation is to perform an absolute calibration of SPICAV.
SOLSPEC is part of the SOLAR payload, mounted on the exterior of the Columbus Module of the ISS and operated by B.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>