<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sun on B.USOC - Belgian User Support and Operations Centre</title>
    <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/tags/sun/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sun on B.USOC - Belgian User Support and Operations Centre</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</webMaster>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 1998 - 2017, B.USOC</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/tags/sun/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Farewell SOLAR!</title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/46/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/46/</guid>
      <description>An event is scheduled in Brussels to share memories with all actors involved in the adventure.
Take part to the farewell event : https://events.oma.be/indico/event/22/
You will can also follow the event on https://livestream.com/ESA/solar
Solar Posters created for the event here
@media (max-width: 767px) {iframe {width:360px;} }</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>B.USOC is happily and proudly starting the 100th Sun Visibility Window of SOLAR</title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/35/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/35/</guid>
      <description>This Observatory onboard the ISS is tracking the Sun now for more than 8 years!
The instrument was designed to work for only 18 months, but it is still running – its operation is exceeding all expectations. Launched at the 2008 minimum of solar cycle 23, it observed the also the maximum of solar cycle 24 in 2015 and now is still active in the decrease phase. Solar energy input to the earth atmosphere and its variations are a major factor in the climate models and are accurately monitored only since the beginning of the space age.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SOLAR in the ISS observes the March 8 total eclipse of the sun</title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/34/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/34/</guid>
      <description>The SOLAR package was active during the March 8 eclipse over Indonesia and measured the progressive dimming of the sun by the moon in three wavelengths, this observation is of course non nominal but analysis by the SOLSPEC science team has already started in order to check the theoretical representation of the spatial distribution of the solar radiation on the solar disk, the observation could also be used in order to perform a verification of the value of the solar diameter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>March 20 eclipse of the sun</title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/27/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/27/</guid>
      <description>SOLAR on the ISS will observe the March 20 eclipse on the sun.
On March 20, there will be a coincidence between the International Space Station orbit and the path of the solar eclipse in Northern Africa. The SOLAR package on the ESA COLUMBUS module of the ISS will observe it. SOLAR operates for 7 years in earth orbit and measures the energy emitted by the sun for the far ultraviolet to the infrared in order to monitor the solar influence on atmospheric chemistry and climate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Download UV DATA&amp;graphics from the Ulisse website</title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/26/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/26/</guid>
      <description>The project ULISSE intends to distribute all the original UV data obtained since 1993 in the frame of the ULISSE metadata.
The project ULISSE intends to distribute all the original UV data obtained since 1993 in the frame of the ULISSE metadata.
SUVIM is a Belgian Institute for Space Aeronomy (IASB-BIRA) network of stations measuring UV solar radiation with several instruments at each station, the network produces several UV radiation group at IASB-BIRA and providing UV indexes and solar irradiances at the stations in quasi-real time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>REVEX picard 2013</title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/8/</guid>
      <description>It is a review of the PICARD operations of 2013.
This review took place on November 27.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SOLAR - Second mission extension achieved</title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/3/</guid>
      <description>Last week, the Safety Review approved the second extension of the SOLAR mission, until February 2017. SOLAR installed on the external platform of Columbus in February 2008 for a nominal mission of one year and half, and was soon extended over February 2013.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SOLAR SOLSPEC collaborating with Venus Express</title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/news/1/</guid>
      <description>On May 17th, a unique collaboration between instruments on the ISS and Venus Express was set up. Between 19h00 and 22h30, SOLSPEC, in Earth-orbit on the ISS, and SPICAV, in Venus-orbit on Venus Express, were simultaneously observing the sun. The goal of this synchronisation is to perform an absolute calibration of SPICAV.
SOLSPEC is part of the SOLAR payload, mounted on the exterior of the Columbus Module of the ISS and operated by B.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>