<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aboutus on B.USOC - Belgian User Support and Operations Centre</title>
    <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/aboutus/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aboutus on B.USOC - Belgian User Support and Operations Centre</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</webMaster>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 1998 - 2017, B.USOC</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/aboutus/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>History and Evolution</title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/aboutus/history/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/aboutus/history/</guid>
      <description>Evolution of the B.USOC Within the timeframe January 2013 to September 2013 and to take into account the results of the Council at ministerial level, the ESA Executive had elaborated on the USOC network, aiming to reduce operation cost and increase efficiency.
In this regard and in order to conduct operations in the European facilities on board the International Space Station (ISS), the European Space Agency had decided to implement a decentralized and hierarchical user centre approach (Figure 1).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Services</title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/aboutus/services/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/aboutus/services/</guid>
      <description>B.USOC&amp;rsquo;s prime customers are Scientific Institutions and Space Agencies with a requirement for advanced manned and non-manned space technologies not exclusively within the field of Microgravity and Space Sciences research.
Engineering Support
Our team of engineers can provide support in the following disciplines:
 Ground control Segment Design support, installation and validation Radio frequency and microwave Cryogenics and vacuum technology Real time embedded control systems Automation and Mechatronics Space mission system engineering  Knowledge Management</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Organization</title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/aboutus/organization/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/aboutus/organization/</guid>
      <description>Institutional
The B.USOC is part of the Ground Segment for the International Space Station (ISS) and is connected to the Manned Spaceflight and Microgravity (MSM) Ground Segment via the Interconnection Ground Subnetwork (IGS).
For the preparation and execution of ISS payload operations, B.USOC works together with Space Applications Services with an integrated team of operations engineers, operators and ground controllers.
The Belgian User Support and Operations Centre (B.USOC) is a structure created by the Belgian Science Policy (BELSPO) and hosted at the Royal Belgian Institute for Space Aeronomy (BIRA-IASB).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>INFRASTRUCTURE</title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/aboutus/infrastructure/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/aboutus/infrastructure/</guid>
      <description>* ESA Operations Room
      Maximize
 GC Room     Maximize
 Solar Laboratory     Maximize
 Microgravity Laboratory           </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goals and Missions</title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/aboutus/goals/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/aboutus/goals/</guid>
      <description>Our missions
 B.USOC supports scientific and technological development through high-quality space operational infrastructures and associated services, to the benefit of Belgian and European higher education and research. B.USOC promotes the development of data processing and knowledge management coming from space experiments and missions.  Our objectives
 To meet the needs of research institutions and their end users as far as space operational infrastructures and services are concerned. To promote space research to all educational and research institutions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Responsibilities</title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/aboutus/responsibilities/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/aboutus/responsibilities/</guid>
      <description>USOC Responsibilities
 Facility and experiment operations preparation, validation, and execution Payload increment planning and inputs to the overall mission/increment/partner plan Operations feasibility and science samples bread-boarding within the Science Reference Model (SRM), collecting science requirements for experiments and payload upgrades Consolidation planning in coordination with industry for ground model utilization (SRM/EM/EGSE) for increment preparation Provision of science/sample based parts of experiment safety data packages, experiment qualification and validation testing, experiment ground and launch site processing Update of PODF, operations scenarios with associated support centres, validation and interface testing of ground segment (Col CC, supporting USOCs, UHBs), experiment ground operations products for launch items Experiment training requirements and procedures, astronaut training support for experiment operations, including instructors, familiarization of scientists Ground-rules and constraints, issue of planning and re-planning requests, inputs to short term plans, timeline and ground data flow Real-time operations management and re-planning for payload and experiments execution, payload team and PI-team coordination, flight anomalies reporting, console logs, payload data processing, ground based experiments on SRM/EM for comparative execution Early retrieval and late access activities, configuration control of experiment ground models, and SRM configuration control  ESA/Industry Responsibilities</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>User Home Base</title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/aboutus/uhb/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/aboutus/uhb/</guid>
      <description>For specific experiment operations, dedicated User Home Bases (UHB) have been set up when required. UHBs, which are the investigator&amp;rsquo;s location at the &amp;laquo;home&amp;raquo; institutes, are typically national institutions (e.g. universities, national centers), which need to obtain the adequate communication and data processing infrastructure allowing real-time data monitoring and control (in some cases) of the respective experiment (e.g. for remote operations).
The B.USOC coordinates and supports this setup, and is the focal point for the operations preparation activities for the UHB, more particularly for the definition of experiment operations requirements, the specifications of hardware, software and the connectivity requirements of the UHB to the ISS ground segment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is the B.USOC</title>
      <link>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/aboutus/about-index/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>social_media@busoc.be (B.USOC)</author>
      <guid>http://www.mistraldesign.be/www.busoc.be/aboutus/about-index/</guid>
      <description>B.USOC is a services centre of the Belgian Science Policy (BELSPO)/R&amp;amp;S division. Our mission is to provide operational services for Belgian scientific institutions and space agencies.
Our dedicated engineering and operations teams carry out experiments on board the International Space Station (ISS) and Satellite ranging from the integration of payloads to their in-orbit operation, astronaut training, processing and dissemination of the scientific data obtained.
B.USOC in short :
 15 years of experience in preparation and operations of ESA experiments &amp;amp; missions Highly experienced engineers, technicians and scientists Ground Control Segment Design support, Installation and Validation Knowledge and Experience in satellite commissioning and operations First decentralized Science Operations Centre for CNES PICARD micro-satellite Assigned by ESA as Facility Responsible Center for ESA/ISS/SOLAR-FSL-METERON-ASIM Knowledge management service focusing on improved performance  About us :</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>